Jose Ferreira

Software Engineer | Web Developer US Army Veteran

New York, NY Cell: 347-327-0034

Email: jferreira590@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/joseferreira5

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jose-ferreira5/

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6),
React.js, Next.js, Node.js, NPM,
Webpack, Express, Git, GitHub,
MongoDB, NoSQL, SQL, MySQL,
PostgreSQL, Firebase, Bootstrap,
AJAX, jQuery, RESTful API,
GraphQL, Handlebars.js, Ruby,
Ruby on Rails, Object Oriented
Programming, Functional
Programming, Object Relational
Mapping, Progressive Web
Applications, Model-View-Controller,
Test Driven Development,
Responsive Web Design

EDUCATION

General Assembly

February 2020 – May 2020 Software Engineering (Certificate)

Columbia Engineering

April 2019 – September 2019 Full-Stack Development (Certificate)

LaGuardia Community College

February 2016 – July 2017 Associate in Arts in Humanities

AWARDS

Army Commendation Medal (x3)
Army Achievement Medal (x2)
Army Good Conduct Medal
Afghanistan Campaign Medal with
Two Campaign Stars
Humanitarian Service Medal
Basic Parachutist Badge

SUMMARY

A solutions-oriented Web Developer and US Army Veteran who holds over 8 years of experience in the supply chain management space. Whether it be solving multi-faceted logistical issues for infantry at war or de-bugging complex errors in code, I take a methodological, detail-oriented approach in developing real-time and effective solutions in high pressure situations. As both an independent self-starter and collaborative team player, I seek the opportunity to work at an organization that places learning, development and teamwork at the center of what they do.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Fellow

General Assembly / New York, NY / February 2020 - Present

- Participated in 500+ hours of applied training in software engineering and web development concepts focusing on Full-Stack Development
- Built skills and fluency in HTML, JavaScript, Node, Express, and other web development frameworks.
- Worked with UX Designers and Software Engineers to create full stack web applications for clients.

Jr. Web Developer | Columbia Engineering Coding Bootcamp Columbia Engineering / New York, NY / April 2019 – September 2019

 Completed 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Logistics Coordinator | Material Handler

Columbia University / New York, NY / September 2017 - February 2020

- Coordinated inbound deliveries of scientific equipment and materials.
- Provided excellent customer support to research teams regarding issues involving critical and time sensitive materials.
- Assisted in the migration to a receiving and tracking cloud-based automated system for logging incoming and outgoing materials.

Unit Supply Sergeant

United States Army / Schofield Barracks, HI / July 2008 - May 2013

- Effectively lead a team of 4 soldiers to support the day-to-day logistics operations for an infantry company.
- Responsible for the accountability and maintenance of over \$500,000 of military equipment.
- Coordinated and organized the movement of essential supplies and equipment over 5 military installations across Afghanistan.